shapefit.com 2012-05-05

# ShapeFit Privacy Policy - Protecting The Privacy of Our Visitors

| 

ShapeFit Privacy Policy - Protecting The Privacy of Our Visitors

At ShapeFit, we respect your privacy and believe you should be informed about how we collect, use and disclose your Personal Information. This Privacy Policy describes our practices regarding how we use and share with third parties Personal Information (as defined below ) that we collect on the Website. By visiting the ShapeFit.com website and any other URLs and websites administered by ShapeFit, LLC and its affiliates (collectively, the “Website”) that are offered by ShapeFit, LLC and its affiliates (collectively, “ShapeFit” or “we” or “us”) or otherwise submitting your Personal Information to us, you accept the practices described in this statement. The terms "you" and "user" as used herein refer to all individuals and/or entities accessing the Website for any reason.

**Terms of Use**  
Your use of the Website is subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy and the [Term of Use](http://www.shapefit.com/terms-conditions.html) (“Terms of Use”), so please read this policy and the [Terms of Use](http://www.shapefit.com/terms-conditions.html) before using the Website. All terms with initial capital letters used in this Privacy Policy but not defined herein have the meanings given them in the Terms of Use. Also review ShapeFit's [Product Liability Waiver](http://www.shapefit.com/product-liability-waiver.html) which covers any products purchased on the ShapeFit.com website or through ShapeFit, LLC directly.

**Age Requirement**  
In order to use the Website you must be at least 18 years of age or the legal age to form a binding contract in your jurisdiction if that age is greater than 18 years of age. Please see the [Terms of Use](http://www.shapefit.com/terms-conditions.html) for additional information regarding this requirement. 

**Personal Information**  
The term “Personal Information” means information that identifies you as an individual, including your name, address, email address, telephone number, age, weight, and gender. We may ask you to submit Personal Information at various places on our Website, including by providing Registration Data, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting feedback. ShapeFit also stores the information you enter about foods, activities, goals, and all other information collected in our online forms. 

We maintain lists of users and use the Personal Information on those lists to contact you or send you information you have requested or that we feel will be of interest to you. We may contact you via phone, email, or postal mail. We generally provide an option for you to choose not to receive these types of communications. However, even if you request not to be contacted by us, we reserve the right to use your contact information if we consider it necessary to send you information about the operation of the site, including information regarding the services you have signed up for on the Website or information about changes to our Privacy Policy. For more information about how to “opt-out” of receiving emails or third party offers, please email us at info@shapefit.com for further details.

Posts submitted to the Community Pages are not confidential and may be viewed by other users and the general public. 

**Non-Personally Identifying Information**  
We may also collect information automatically about the use of the Website, through, for example, “cookies” or “IP addresses” (as described below). ShapeFit also archives log files and uses non-personally identifying information in aggregate form to detect errors with the Website, identify security issues, build higher quality, more useful online services by performing statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of ShapeFit users, and measure demographics and interests in connection with specific areas of the Website. We may provide such statistical data to our advertisers, affiliates and other current and potential business partners. For example, we may inform these third parties as to the number of people who have seen and clicked on links to their websites. We also use such data to create a more enjoyable experience for our users, for example, to assist in selecting content and advertisers featured on specific channels, pages and site areas based on your general likes and dislikes. 

“Cookies” are small files websites place on your hard drive that allow websites to identify you. For example, if you allow a website to remember your login name or password, the website places a cookie on your computer. Cookies cannot read any other information on your hard drive. We may place cookies on your computer to allow us to identify you when you visit the Website. We may use cookies to measure Website traffic, to offer you certain services, or to customize your visit. However, if you do not wish to receive cookies, or want to be notified of when they are placed, your browser may permit you to do so. An “IP address” is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. In some cases your IP address stays the same from browser session to browser session; but if you use a consumer internet access provider, your IP address probably varies from session to session. 

**Use of Contractors and Service Providers**  
ShapeFit uses third parties (including contractors and service providers) to help with certain aspects of its operations, which may require disclosure of your Personal Information to them. For example, ShapeFit may use a third party to communicate with you (via telephone, email, or letter) about our services, to send information to you, to host the Website and related databases, and to perform other work that we may choose to outsource. ShapeFit requires these third parties to use your Personal Information only as necessary to perform the services they are asked to perform. 

The ads appearing on the Website are delivered to you by a third party. Information about your visits to the Website, such as the number of times you have viewed an ad, and your age, weight, gender, goals and region may be used to tailor the ads that are served to you. ShapeFit does not share your name or email address with advertisers, unless you specifically select to share information to receive an offer. In the course of serving advertisements to the Website, third party advertisers may also place cookies on your computer. However, if you do not wish to receive cookies, or want to be notified of when they are placed, your browser may permit you to do so. For more information about how to “opt-out” of receiving emails or third party offers, please email us at info@shapefit.com for further details.

 **Corporate Family**  
We may share some or all of your Personal Information with any current or future “affiliate” (which means a parent company, a subsidiary, joint venture, or other company that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with ShapeFit), in which case we will require the affiliate to honor this privacy policy. If another company acquires ShapeFit (or a business unit of ShapeFit that uses your Personal Information), the Personal Information collected by ShapeFit will be transferred to that company and it will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy. 

**Security**   
We use industry-standard measures to protect the Personal Information you share with us from unauthorized access or disclosure. However, you should know that no company, including ShapeFit, can fully eliminate security or other risks associated with the possession of Personal Information. For example, we may be legally required to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your login information and password. 

**Modifications to the Privacy Policy**  
We may make changes to the Privacy Policy from time to time in our sole discretion. We will post any such changes on the Website along with a notice on the Website that such changes have been made. Your continued use of the Web Site following the posting of such changes constitutes your acceptance of any such changes. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, or any revised versions thereof, you may not use the Website. 

**Queries**   
If you have a question or comment about the ShapeFit site or a request to correct or delete your Personal Information, please contact us at info@shapefit.com. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to fulfill your request in a timely manner. However, please be aware that even if ShapeFit deletes such Personal Information from its ‘live’ databases, such information may still be stored on other databases (including those kept for archival purposes).

| 

| 

| Our database of over 500 exercise guides lets you choose the right exercises for your workouts. It's like having your own personal online fitness trainer! [**Go >>**](http://www.shapefit.com/training.html)  
---|---  

| Over 300 weight loss success stories from real people who have successfully lost weight. They share tips about their diet plans and workout routines! [**Go >>**](http://www.shapefit.com/success-stories.html)  
---|---  

| Are you ready to build muscle & burn fat? Download your FREE ShapeFit eBooks today and learn diet and exercise secrets to pack on muscle and get ripped! [**Go >>**](http://www.shapefit.com/free-fitness-ebooks.html)  
---|---  

| Read interviews and see photos from fitness models and figure competitors. They reveal top diet and exercise secrets to build muscle and burn fat! [**Go >>**](http://www.shapefit.com/fitness-models.html)  
---|---  

| FitTracker will track and analyze every aspect of your fitness program and it has amazing features to take the guesswork out of getting into shape! [**Go >>**](http://fittracker.shapefit.com/)  
---|---  

| Watch over 100 exercise videos and learn the best workout routines and exercises to implement into your fitness plan to build muscle, gain strength and get huge! [**Go >>**](http://www.shapefit.com/exercise-videos.html)  
---|---  

| Our fast food restaurant database will show you how many calories and fat grams are packed into your favorite fast food meals. You will be in for a surprise! ****[**Go >>**](http://www.shapefit.com/fastfood.html)  
---|---  

| Our fitness calculators will show you how many calories you need to eat, help you find your target heart rate zone and learn how many calories are in your meals! [**Go >>**](http://www.shapefit.com/calculators.html)  
---|---  

| Read different fitness questions and answers about a wide array of diet and exercise concerns from our visitors who need help building muscle and burning fat! [**Go >>**](http://www.shapefit.com/fitness-questions-answers.html)  
---|---  

| We offer exercise equipment that is the perfect choice for anyone who wants to get a great full body workout anywhere without spending a lot of money! [**Go >>**](http://www.shapefit.com/shapefit-fitness-products.html)  
---|---
